<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>codedbearder</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/tags/arm</link><description>Recent content https://codedbearder.com/tags/arm</description><generator>nixtml</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://codedbearder.com/tags/arm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 16:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Making NanoPI R4S booting sane with SPI Flash</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/posts/nanopi-r4s-spi-flash</link><guid>https://codedbearder.com/posts/nanopi-r4s-spi-flash</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;There's one thing I really don't like about many popular ARM SBCs (Single Board Computers) that for some reason has been deemed acceptable and that is the lack of on-board flash for storing the bootloader. This means that the bootloader (most often u-boot) needs to be written to a specific location on the SD card or eMMC (if available). Generally distributions for such boards offer an image for download that can be written as is to the boot medium, including the bootloader, requiring such images to be created for &lt;em&gt;each supported SBC&lt;/em&gt;. Wouldn't it be nice if we could just pop in a generic installer USB stick where we can partition the drive as needed before installing, like is done with generic x86 computers?&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>TX3 Mini: Mainline Linux on an Android TV Box</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/posts/mainline-linux-on-tx3-mini</link><guid>https://codedbearder.com/posts/mainline-linux-on-tx3-mini</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;I've always found Raspberry Pi cases and the Pi's connector locations to be rather aesthetically unpleasing, with the power connector coming out from the side and the ethernet from the back (or vice versa). Imagine my excitement when I was browsing the &lt;a href="https://github.com/torvalds/linux"&gt;github mirror of Linux&lt;/a&gt; (as you do) and I ran into a dts for an Android TV box called Tanix TX3 Mini.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item></channel></rss>