<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>codedbearder</title><link>https://codedbearder.com</link><description>Recent content https://codedbearder.com</description><generator>nixtml</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://codedbearder.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>I made a new backplane for my Terramaster F2-221 NAS</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/posts/f3-backplane</link><guid>https://codedbearder.com/posts/f3-backplane</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://codedbearder.com/posts/nixos-terramaster-f2-221"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about how I setup NixOS on my Terramaster F2-221 instead of using the included TOS provided by Terramaster. This in itself was quite simple as the NAS contains Intel J3355, a standard X86_64 CPU. However the NAS only has 2 SATA connectors, both of which were being used for the 4TB hard drives, so I had to resort to plugging in an external USB SSD for storing the operating system. This quickly became a little annoying to make room for this external SSD behind the NAS and make sure it's always plugged in when something is moved around in the shelf where I keep it, so I wanted to see if I could come up with a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Making NanoPI R4S booting sane with SPI Flash</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/posts/nanopi-r4s-spi-flash</link><guid>https://codedbearder.com/posts/nanopi-r4s-spi-flash</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;There's one thing I really don't like about many popular ARM SBCs (Single Board Computers) that for some reason has been deemed acceptable and that is the lack of on-board flash for storing the bootloader. This means that the bootloader (most often u-boot) needs to be written to a specific location on the SD card or eMMC (if available). Generally distributions for such boards offer an image for download that can be written as is to the boot medium, including the bootloader, requiring such images to be created for &lt;em&gt;each supported SBC&lt;/em&gt;. Wouldn't it be nice if we could just pop in a generic installer USB stick where we can partition the drive as needed before installing, like is done with generic x86 computers?&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>I wrote a keyboard remapper for wayland</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/posts/writing-keyboard-remapper-wayland</link><guid>https://codedbearder.com/posts/writing-keyboard-remapper-wayland</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I bought a new laptop with the intention of running Linux with Sway as my WM. This is the setup I run on my workstation where I have a 60% keyboard on which I use caps lock as a function key for a second layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because muscle memory is a thing I have been using Karabiner Elements to remap the keyboard on my work macbook pro but I could not find a suitable alternative for Linux when using a Wayland compositor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Running NixOS on a consumer NAS</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/posts/nixos-terramaster-f2-221</link><guid>https://codedbearder.com/posts/nixos-terramaster-f2-221</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;I have an old whitebox server sporting a Xeon E5 (v1) that I'd like to get rid of. It's running a handful of VMs on Proxmox. Most of them I can get rid of by moving their services to Kubernetes, but I wasn't sure what I wanted to do with my NAS VM and Plex server. The latter you can easily run in Kubernetes but I'm not planning on having particularly powerful nodes and I need transcoding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>TX3 Mini: Mainline Linux on an Android TV Box</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/posts/mainline-linux-on-tx3-mini</link><guid>https://codedbearder.com/posts/mainline-linux-on-tx3-mini</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;I've always found Raspberry Pi cases and the Pi's connector locations to be rather aesthetically unpleasing, with the power connector coming out from the side and the ethernet from the back (or vice versa). Imagine my excitement when I was browsing the &lt;a href="https://github.com/torvalds/linux"&gt;github mirror of Linux&lt;/a&gt; (as you do) and I ran into a dts for an Android TV box called Tanix TX3 Mini.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item></channel></rss>