<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>codedbearder</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/tags/nas</link><description>Recent content https://codedbearder.com/tags/nas</description><generator>nixtml</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://codedbearder.com/tags/nas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>I made a new backplane for my Terramaster F2-221 NAS</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/posts/f3-backplane</link><guid>https://codedbearder.com/posts/f3-backplane</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://codedbearder.com/posts/nixos-terramaster-f2-221"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about how I setup NixOS on my Terramaster F2-221 instead of using the included TOS provided by Terramaster. This in itself was quite simple as the NAS contains Intel J3355, a standard X86_64 CPU. However the NAS only has 2 SATA connectors, both of which were being used for the 4TB hard drives, so I had to resort to plugging in an external USB SSD for storing the operating system. This quickly became a little annoying to make room for this external SSD behind the NAS and make sure it's always plugged in when something is moved around in the shelf where I keep it, so I wanted to see if I could come up with a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Running NixOS on a consumer NAS</title><link>https://codedbearder.com/posts/nixos-terramaster-f2-221</link><guid>https://codedbearder.com/posts/nixos-terramaster-f2-221</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;I have an old whitebox server sporting a Xeon E5 (v1) that I'd like to get rid of. It's running a handful of VMs on Proxmox. Most of them I can get rid of by moving their services to Kubernetes, but I wasn't sure what I wanted to do with my NAS VM and Plex server. The latter you can easily run in Kubernetes but I'm not planning on having particularly powerful nodes and I need transcoding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item></channel></rss>